yourstory.in 2018-10-02

# Privacy Policy (Latest) - YourStory Media Pvt. Ltd.

At YourStory Media Private Limited, we respect your need for online privacy and protect any Personal Information that you may share with us, in an appropriate manner. This privacy policy ("Privacy Policy") applies to those who visit our website www.yourstory.com owned and operated by YourStory Media Private Limited, as well as users of our on-demand services delivered via our mobile app or mobile site ("Services"). As a condition to use of Services, you consent to the terms of the Privacy Policy Statement as it may be updated from time to time.

### Information Recorded and Used

From May 25, 2018, The General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR) is effective and we at YourStory are committed to protecting information that we collect in the best possible manner. In order to comply with the GDPR we have planned for some changes that include:

  * Opt - in:  Where we control the information, we will ensure that your consent is taken before the information is collected. You will also be able to review our updated privacy policy
  * Updating our legal agreements to ensure they are GDPR compliant
  * Updating our systems and processes to meet the requirements of GDPR

YourStory may, if you so choose, send direct mailers to you at the address given by you. You have the option to ‘opt-out’ of this direct mailer by way of links provided at the bottom of each mailer. We respect your privacy and in the event that you choose to not receive such mailers, we will take all steps to remove you from the list.

We transfer information about you if YourStory is acquired by or merged with another company.

We believe it is necessary to share information in order to investigate, prevent, or take action regarding illegal activities, suspected fraud, situations involving potential threats to the physical safety of any person, or as otherwise required by law.

### Information Sharing on Campaigns

User data collected by YourStory on a microsite as part of a campaign and consented to be shared by the user, shall be shared with the sponsor of the microsite.

#### Personal Information

During the Registration Process for creating a user account, we request for your name and email address or phone number. You may also be asked to choose a username and a password, which will be used solely for the purpose of providing access to your user account. Your name, email address and phone number will be used to inform you regarding new services, releases, upcoming events and changes in this Privacy Policy Statement.

YourStory Media will have access to third party personal information provided by you as part of using Services such as contacts in your phonebook. This information may include third party names, email addresses, phone numbers and physical addresses and will be used for servicing your requirements as expressed by you to YourStory Media and solely as part and parcel of your use of Services. We do not share this third party personal information with anyone for promotional purposes, nor do we utilize it for any purposes not expressly consented to by you.

We post user testimonials on our website. These testimonials may include names and other Personal Information and we acquire permission from our users prior to posting these on our website. YourStory Media is not responsible for the Personal Information users elect to post within their testimonials.

#### Usage Details

Your usage details such as time, frequency, duration and pattern of use, features used and the amount of storage used will be recorded by us in order to enhance your experience of the Services and to help us provide you the best possible service.

#### Contents of your User Account

We store and maintain fil and other data stored in your user account at AWS, Singapore . In order to prevent loss of data due to errors or system failures, we also keep backup copies of data including the contents of your user account. Hence your files and data may remain on our servers even after deletion or termination of your user account. We may retain and use your Personal Information and data as necessary to comply with our legal obligations, resolve disputes, and enforce our rights. We assure you that the contents of your user account will not be disclosed to anyone and will not be accessible even to employees of YourStory Media except in circumstances specifically mentioned in this Privacy Policy Statement and Terms of Services. We also do not scan the contents of your user account for serving targeted advertisements.

#### Payment Information

In case of services requiring payment, we request credit card or other payment account information, which will be used solely for processing payments. Your financial information will not be stored by us except for the name and address of the card holder, the expiry date and the last four digits of the Credit Card number. Subject to your prior consent and where necessary for processing future payments, your financial information will be stored in encrypted form on secure servers of our reputed Payment Gateway Service Provider who is beholden to treating your Personal Information in accordance with this Privacy Policy Statement.

#### Visitor Details

We use the Internet Protocol address, browser type, browser language, referring URL, files accessed, errors generated, time zone, operating system and other visitor details collected in our log files to analyze the trends, administer the website, track visitor's movements and to improve our website. We link this automatically collected data to other information we collect about you.

#### Analytics

YourStory Media uses third party softwares for analytics. All metrics information collected from your usage of the Service shall be transmitted to analytics provider. This information is then used to evaluate how users use Service, and to compile statistical reports on activity for us

We further use the same statistical analytics tool to track or to collect your Personally Information. We will use this information in order to maintain, enhance, or add to the functionality of the Service and to personalize the experience for you. Anonymized and aggregated information and analysis may be made public where desired by YourStory Media .

#### Children's Personal Information

YourStory Media does not knowingly collect any personal information from children under the age of 13. If you are under the age of 13, please do not submit any personal information through our website or Service. We encourage parents and legal guardians to monitor their children's Internet usage and to help enforce this policy by instructing their children never to provide personal information through our Service or website without their permission. If you have reason to believe that a child under the age of 13 has provided personal information to YourStory Media, please contact us.

#### Cookies and Other Tracking Technologies

We use Local Storage Objects (LSOs) such as HTML5 to store content information, preferences and to keep you signed-in. Third parties with whom we partner to provide certain features on our site or to display advertising based upon your Web browsing activity use LSOs such as HTML5 to collect and store information. Various browsers may offer their own management tools for removing HTML5 LSOs.

We use temporary and permanent cookies to enhance your experience of our services. Temporary cookies will be removed from your computer each time you close your browser. If you have turned cookies off, you may not be able to use registered areas of the website. Technologies such as: cookies, beacons, tags and scripts are used by YourStory Media Private Limited and our partners, affiliates, or service providers. These technologies are used in analyzing trends, administering the site, tracking users' movements around the site and to gather demographic information about our user base as a whole. We may receive reports based on the use of these technologies by these companies on an individual as well as aggregated basis.

#### Behavioral Targeting/ Re-Targeting

We partner with third parties to manage our advertisements on other sites. Our third party partners may use technologies such as cookies to gather information about your activities on this site and other sites in order to provide you advertising based upon your browsing activities and interests.

#### Links from our website

Some pages of our website contain external links. You are advised to verify the privacy practices of such other websites. We are not responsible for the manner of use or misuse of information made available by you at such other websites. We encourage you not to provide Personal Information, without assuring yourselves of the Privacy Policy Statement of other websites.

#### With whom we share Information

We may need to share your Personal Information and your data to our affiliates, resellers, service providers and business partners solely for the purpose of providing our services to you. The purposes for which we may disclose your Personal Information or data to our service providers may include, but are not limited to, data storage, database management, web analytics and payment processing. These service providers are authorized to use your Personal Information or data only as necessary to provide these services to us. In such cases YourStory Media does not ensure that such affiliates, resellers, service providers and business partners comply with this Privacy Policy Statement and adopt appropriate confidentiality and security measures. We will obtain your prior specific consent before we share your Personal Information or data to any person outside YourStory Media for any purpose that is not directly connected with providing our services to you. We will share your Personal Information with third parties only in the ways that are described in this Privacy Policy Statement. We do not sell your Personal Information to third parties. We may share generic aggregated demographic information not linked to any Personal Information regarding visitors and users with our business partners and advertisers.

#### Legal Disclosure

Please be aware that laws in various jurisdictions in which we operate may obligate us to disclose user information and the contents of your user account to the local law enforcement authorities under a legal process or an enforceable government request. In addition, we may also disclose Personal Information and contents of your user account to law enforcement authorities if such disclosure is determined to be necessary by YourStory Media in our sole and absolute discretion for protecting the safety of our users, employees, or the general public. If YourStory Media is involved in a merger, acquisition, or sale of all or a portion of its business or assets, you will be notified via email and/or a prominent notice on our website of any change in ownership or uses of your Personal Information, as well as any choices you may have regarding your Personal Information.

#### How secure is your Information

We adopt industry appropriate data collection, storage and processing practices and security measures, as well as physical security measures to protect against unauthorized access, alteration, disclosure or destruction of your Personal Information, username, password, transaction information and data stored in your user account. Access to your name and email address is restricted to our employees who need to know such information in connection with providing Services to you and are bound by confidentiality obligations.

#### Your Choice in Information Use

In the event we decide to use your Personal Information for any purpose other than as stated in this Privacy Policy Statement, we will offer you an effective way to opt out of the use of your Personal Information for those other purposes. From time to time, we may send emails to you regarding new services, releases and upcoming events. You may opt out of receiving newsletters and other secondary messages from YourStory Media by selecting the 'unsubscribe' function present in every email we send[D4] . However, you will continue to receive essential transactional emails.

#### Accessing, Updating and Removing Personal Information

Upon request, we will provide you with information about whether we hold any of your Personal Information. Users who wish to correct, update or remove any Personal Information including those from a public forum, directory or testimonial on our site may do so either by accessing their user account.

#### Investigation of Illegal Activity

We may need to provide access to your Personal Information and the contents of your user account to our employees and service providers for the purpose of investigating any suspected illegal activity or potential violation of the terms and conditions for use of Services. However, YourStory Media will ensure that such access is in compliance with this Privacy Policy Statement and subject to appropriate confidentiality and security measures.

#### Enforcement of Privacy Policy

We make every effort to ensure that Personal Information provided by you is used in conformity with this Privacy Policy Statement. If you have any concerns regarding our adherence to this Privacy Policy Statement or the manner in which Personal Information is used for the purpose of providing Services, kindly contact us at support@yourstory.com. We will contact you to address your concerns and we will also cooperate with regulatory authorities in this regard if needed.

#### Amendments

Amendments to this Policy will be posted to this URL and will be effective when posted. You should frequently visit this Policy to check for amendments. Your continued use of this Website or the Service following the posting of any amendment, modification, or change to this Policy shall constitute your acceptance of the amendments to this Policy. You can choose to discontinue use of the Website or Service, if you do not accept the terms of this Policy, or any modified version of this Policy.

#### External widgets

We provide the users third party widgets such as Facebook and Twitter buttons on the website that allow users to share articles and other information on different platforms. These widgets may collect your IP address, which page you are visiting on our site, and may set a cookie to enable the widgets to function properly. These widgets do not collect or store any Personal Information from users on the website and simply act as a bridge for your convenience in sharing information. Your interactions with these widgets are governed by the privacy policy of the company providing it.
